Spotted offshore of Haneda Airport.
We've got a pleasure craft adrift
in the open.
Hamanami. Roger that.
Pleasure craft confirmed.
No apparent hull damage.
The Glory-Maru.
MJG-15041.
Requesting owner information.
Boarding the vessel.
Hello? Is anyone here?
No one on the top deck!
No signs of life.
Just some personal effects.
No traces of an incident.
Perhaps they fell overboard?
The vessel's vacant. We'll prepare a tow.
Huh? What is that?
Whoa. whoa. Wait. Wait. wait. wait!
The report came in
from Intelligence and Research.
There's flooding in the Aqua-Line tunnel
due to a crack in the ceiling.
Water's currently pouring onto
the auto lanes and trapping vehicles.
I've gotten word that a liaison office
is up and running.
and an emergency order
has already been issued.
And the Prime Minister?
Scheduled to arrive in 28 minutes.
- We need intel now. Let's head downstairs.
- Right.
First report confirmed at about 8:30 a.m.
Leak in the Tokyo Aqua-Line tunnel.
near the 2.5 kilo marker.
Seawater entering from a fissure...
- Keep me updated as you get new info.
- Right.
Several cars trapped
and damaged by the flood.
Emergency crews are currently
on the scene.
Several Hamanami Coast Guard personnel
were caught in the steam cloud
that's rising in the bay.
The Aqua-Line has been shut down
in both directions.
The Coast Guard has issued safety alerts
throughout the region.
What's the situation. Mr. Koriyama?
A total of five collisions in the tunnel
have been confirmed so far.
Do we know if it was an earthquake
that caused the flooding?
We haven't received
the seismic readings yet.
Is there any correlation between this
and the sea eruption?
With limited info. we can't say for sure.
We've just received aerial footage.
So. it really is just an underwater
volcanic eruption then?
That's not a normal eruption.
This is Coast Guard 691.
reporting continued steam eruptions
in the bay.
The churning water prevents
undersea visibility.
so the situation underwater
cannot be confirmed.
The situation's unpredictable.
What we need is a unified response.
Let's put our heads together
and reorganize.
The former liaison office
is now the Prime Minister's
response office.
The FDMA disaster task force
has been established.
3rd Regional
Coast Guard has sealed the bay.
No sea or air access.
The MLIT has notified residents
in the nearby coastal areas
that they should evacuate.
An evacuation advisory has been issued.
Please evacuate the premises immediately.
Follow police instructions.
For your own safety.
board the train headed towards Kisarazu.
Water's still pouring in.
It's dangerous.
What should I do about my car?
This way. and watch your head
on the way down.
Oh. cool. a slide.
- Whoa!
- What's going on?
Remain calm.
We're heading
to the first aid station now.
- This place is kind of sick.
- If you're able to walk.
- please do so.
- I don't want to. My feet hurt.
This is awesome.
Getting the scoop before anyone else.
Can you come over here for a moment?
- Wait. wait. wait.
- What is that?
- What?
- What's that noise?
Ah. seems like something's up there.
Departing planes will return
to the terminal for now.
- This is bad.
- Please stay calm and seat...
This is seriously starting
to freak me out.
Huh? What's that?
There's something there.
Sir. the Prime Minister has returned.
Therefore. the cause
of the Aqua-Line rupture
is still under investigation.
Never mind the details.
- Were there any fatalities or not?
- None.
Then just let the guys below deal with it.
We can't.
There's secondary disaster risk after all.
I've canceled your meeting
with the Secretary General
so you can attend the briefing
that begins in five minutes.
I see. Understood.
This event indicates the presence of
some kind of undersea thermal discharge.
but can anyone provide a possible cause?
How about an unidentified nuclear
submarine accident. or a meltdown?
In the bay? It's shallow and not suited
to larger vessels. let alone a submarine.
We think the water was heated by magma
to cause a kind of vapor explosion.
In other words. a new undersea
volcanic eruption is likely the cause.
Uh. Mr. Yanagihara.
It looks like the epicenter
of the explosion is shallow.
and the ejecta are allegedly
just water vapor.
therefore this can't technically
be recognized as volcanic.
You didn't think
to share that info sooner?
Forgive me.
What if it was a large hydrothermal vent
that appeared out of nowhere?
That's good. I like that theory.
However.
it's located directly above the tunnel.
A vent in a location
that's been geologically surveyed
would be hard to believe.
So it's an oversight.
That's not unheard of.
Prime Minister...
the seafloor...
there is something's on the seafloor.
There's something? Like what?
A giant creature's my assumption.
There's even footage of it
you can look up online.
Preposterous. Are you saying this thing
is just a big whale spouting?
The seawater is boiling.
There's no creature with a body
temperature over a hundred degrees.
We've been scouring online videos as well.
Prime Minister.
We've yet to find any conclusive evidence
as to what caused the flooding.
We're wasting time here. so let's do this.
Why don't we focus
on narrowing down our choices?
That's right. So we have a new undersea
volcano or a large hydrothermal vent.
There's nothing else it could be.
Then next on our list is not only
putting together a basic response.
we should also gather the relevant
cabinet ministers for a meeting.
Will that be sufficient?
Right. Good idea.
In that case. let's move to
the main conference room. everyone.
We have to stay on top of this situation.
Yaguchi.
Everything's set so all you can do now
is toe the line on their decision.
Don't stir things up. you got that?
I just think we should consider
every single possibility there is.
I get that you're rebellious.
but think of the position of the guy
who recommended you.
A warning. Do what you will with it.
The transportation of all those injured
has been completed
and they're receiving care.
Fireboats and information-gathering
helicopters have been dispatched
to Tokyo Bay and stand ready to respond.
We're prepared for any situation.
That's all.
Regarding the coastal region
of Tokyo Bay.
Due to the risk of damage from debris
and ash caused by the eruption.
we've begun evacuation preparations.
and we're grounding all flights
out of Haneda Airport.
We're taking thorough
crisis management measures.
Forgive me. An addendum.
Uh... The grounding of all flights
out of Haneda
is a necessary measure to prioritize
citizen safety over any economic losses.
We've deduced that a new undersea volcano
is believed to be the cause
of the tunnel flooding accident.
Fortunately. not a single trace
of toxic gases has been detected so far.
We're sending research teams from
both the Meteorological Agency
and the Coast Guard
to investigate the site.
They'll conduct a thorough investigation
there and report back as soon as possible.
Oh.
Everyone. we've just received a report
that eruption activity
is dying down rapidly.
That's good.
Does that mean it's over?
Mm. guess it was nothing
Prime Minister.
I must reiterate something.
It's still possible that the cause of
the accident is a giant marine creature.
I'd like everyone here to consider this.
Yaguchi. this is a cabinet meeting.
No place for jokes.
Everything's going on record.
Do you want to embarrass us?
There is no such marine creature!
And that's to be as expected.
No time frame for restoration
or prospect or recovery means...
- Sir?
- Hmm?
There's been another incident.
You should turn on the TV.
...expect those losses to continue
to increase in the future.
Sorry. We have to delay
this discussion for now.
The television. Turn on the TV now.
This is unbelievable!
I've never seen anything like it!
We've captured footage of an object that
suddenly breached the surface of the sea
and stretched into the sky!
Wh-what could that be. do you think?
- It could be..?
- It's definitely a tail.
Yaguchi's joke is a serious matter
after all. wouldn't you say?
Let us officially adjourn here
due to the change in situation.
All relevant ministers should head
to the Prime Minister's office right away.
...from an Eyewitness News helicopter.
So. what is that?
A Giant Unidentified Life-Form.
Prime Minister.
Well. that's only what
we're calling it for now.
But currently. uh. we're gathering
biologists and scholars
from various fields.
which includes the ministry.
as well as universities
and research institutes.
We'll narrow down the candidates.
hold an emergency expert meeting
to ascertain what this thing is
and what we should call it.
We need to know right away.
- Do all you can.
- Right.
Prime Minister.
We should concentrate
our response to all this.
wouldn't you agree?
Uh. yes. I do.
However. this is way more unexpected
than we thought.
Yet our choices for the response
are quite simple. I think.
We can try to capture it
and exterminate it.
Do what we can to drive it away.
or we can choose to do nothing at all
and just let it go.
In that case. I vote for extermination.
And I concur.
Setting aside the connection
to the tunnel accident for a minute.
there's the closing of Tokyo Bay
as well as the grounding
of all Haneda flights.
so we're already looking at
huge economic losses.
I agree. I vote to exterminate it.
Me. too. We should get rid of it
as soon as possible.
Right. Defense Minister?
Uh...
While there have been deployments
in the past
for the purpose of exterminating
harmful animals.
our forces have technically
never used firearms in Tokyo Bay.
so we're unsure.
Why murder it?
Can we not just get rid of it?
Peacefully chase it off?
Prime Minister.
Environmental protection groups
and academic societies.
several of them have weighed in
saying that the creature
should be regarded as a new species.
They want nets in the bay
so it can be captured alive.
No. we have to kill it.
Why don't we just use some torpedoes
or something?
I understand your feelings on the matter.
however. the sanctioned use of weapons
requires careful consideration.
Out of our current options.
I'd like to ask that you strongly consider
live capture.
Start gathering information
on the giant unknown creature right now.
Consider each case scenario.
individual responses for its seizure.
removal and execution.
Sorry. which of us were you talking to?
It appears that a vapor cloud has started
moving towards the Tama River.
Huh? It's moving?
Well. it's alive. isn't it?
The giant unknown creature
is just off Haneda Airport near runway D.
It's entering the Tama River.
We just got a report of flooding on
the Bayshore Expressway. Damage unknown.
The hell is going on?
Maybe don't capture it?
Prime Minister.
three biologists have arrived.
I recommend that we go
consult with them immediately.
Hard to tell what it is
from the TV footage alone.
Whether it's a dinosaur
or a subspecies of whale.
We can't identify it with this footage.
It seems to me that this creature
is a new aquatic species.
Yet I can't say for certain
without examining the creature for myself.
I'm concerned about whether or not
this footage is even real.
If I made a judgment
that was based on unverified evidence...
then I'd lose credibility as a biologist.
The meeting's wrapping up.
We'll resume in five minutes.
This is getting ridiculous.
What a waste of time that was.
Those so-called experts were useless.
- I agree.
- I couldn't care less about status.
Just get someone who actually
knows something.
Will do.
- Shimura.
- Yes?
Who can we call?
I have a college friend over
at the Ministry of the Environment
who would know about this.
but she's still low ranking.
I don't mind. Call her right away.
This creature. while it does walk.
it looks like its default
is a snake-like movement.
We can deduce that it's aquatic
judging by the shape of its gills.
however. it also has legs like a lungfish.
If this thing has legs.
is it possible it can come on land?
Yes. It is a possibility.
Is that true? What's going on?
Well. frankly. we have yet to officially
decide which agency it falls under.
Our scholar says
that even if it had finlike feet.
an aquatic creature's internal organs
and bones would be unable to handle
the full force of gravity on land.
As a result. it would be crushed
by its own weight. so I think we're safe.
I appreciate that assertion.
however. I think it's already
supporting its own weight.
Is that true?
What do you think. Environment Minister?
Uh. uh. yes.
Uh. please forgive my Deputy Chief's
lack of decorum today.
Just as your experts have
already concluded.
I believe the creature coming on land
is very improbable.
I see.
Prime Minister. considering the extent
of the destruction so far.
I recommend that we hold
an emergency press conference
to calm the nation's citizens.
ideally as soon as possible.
Not just that. During the conference.
it's crucial that we disclose
only what is necessary. and clarify.
that it's verified information.
Understood.
Get my emergency response uniform.
The Giant Unidentified Life-Form
has caused significant damage
to both the Aqua-Line
and Tama River tunnels.
It's currently migrating up
the Nomi River in Ota Ward.
While we've yet to identify
what sort of creature it is.
we don't expect it
to ever come out of the water.
Even if it were to beach itself.
we think that by the time it reaches the
shallow water. it'll likely be crushed.
The creature would be crushed to death
under its own weight.
I repeat. there's no immediate danger
of the creature coming ashore.
So beloved citizens of Tokyo.
I ask that you set your minds at ease.
Prime Minister.
please excuse the interruption.
Sir. the creature has come on shore.
Huh?! Are you sure?
What was the point?
You said there was no immediate danger.
What do we do now?
I just lied on national television.
That's why we asked that you
please not change the wording
or go off script and just read it as is.
I needed to reassure the public.
That's what a good leader does.
You're right. of course.
We're waiting to hear back
from our experts
on how the creature made landfall.
I don't care about that.
What's the current situation?
Prime Minister.
I strongly suggest we arrange
an emergency disaster control
headquarters right away.
Then do it.
This cabinet meeting
is now officially adjourned.
Well. everyone. that's all for now.
We want to get rid of
all these formal meetings.
but we have to have a meeting
in order to do that.
Yes. it's inefficient.
but it's all for documentation.
which is democracy's foundation.
Still. we can't even hold a press
conference without having to go all out.
Regarding the Giant Unidentified Life-Form
that has landed in Tokyo.
the government has established an
emergency disaster control headquarters
for the sole purpose of combating it.
We are crafting a full-scale response
to ensure that all possible measures
are taken to ensure the safety
of the people.
This includes being in close contact
with Tokyo and federal government agencies
in order to carry out
a coordinated evacuation.
Furthermore...
The Giant Unidentified Life-Form
is currently heading to Shinagawa Ward.
We're clocking its average speed at about
13 kilometers per hour.
For something so large.
it moves very slowly.
Even so. it could trample through the
whole capital in three hours at this pace.
I guess Tokyo's surprisingly small
and fragile.
This is bad.
We are looking at catastrophic damage.
That's why we need
to exterminate it already.
It's a densely-populated part of the city.
Evacuations of the citizens should
really take priority.
The MIC and the MLIT need
to start working on evacuation zones
and transportation methods.
We've received orders
from the Prime Minister
to conduct evacuation measures.
possibly shadow evacuation.
Why didn't they issue an evacuation order
right away?
This is unprecedented.
Nothing in the first response manual
applies here.
The first response manual
has always been useless.
That case. you draft an order on the fly.
We haven't undergone any
disaster prevention training
for an event like this.
And if we want to avoid nationwide panic.
do not call for a wide evacuation area.
The city residents are gonna have
to evacuate themselves.
We'll give it our all
to control traffic at the scene
to get everyone out efficiently.
This traffic light is out of order.
Please leave your vehicles immediately.
Follow the instructions of the police
and other safety personnel.
Attention.
The Tokyo Metropolitan Government
has ordered the full evacuation
of Shinagawa Ward.
All residents are required
to quickly evacuate the area.
Honey. we have to get going!
At this rate. the city will be in ruins.
We need to contact the NPSC.
If the federal government doesn't act.
then we'll have to request
the Self-Defense Forces
to eradicate this thing for our security.
They want to use weapons?
If they do. we interpret this
as an armed attack under Article 76.
then a defense mobilization
allows the use of force.
This doesn't technically qualify
as an armed attack.
Article 76 stipulates the case
of the attacker as a foreign nation
or something equivalent.
which means this doesn't count.
Monsters don't count.
I'm sure you're aware that wording
is the least of our concerns.
No matter how you look at it.
only the SDF can deal with this.
But that would mean soldiers engaging
in a battle in the city.
Well. that'll certainly give
the Prime Minister pause.
An integrated response.
We need to integrate
all parts of our response
including both deploying Self-Defense
Forces and citizen evacuation.
That's why I think you should declare
a state of emergency. Prime Minister.
It appears we're left with only one thing
we can do.
Mobilization for defense
as an extralegal measure.
However. only the Prime Minister can make
that decision.
You're suggesting a proclamation
that has never been issued before. ever.
In addition.
we'd be mobilizing our country for war.
The evacuation.
One of this size will undoubtedly
be difficult for police forces.
Mobilizing defense has its risks.
Consider the residents who aren't
able to flee in the middle of combat.
which means collateral damage.
No. no. Not that.
How about the U.S. forces that are here?
What if we have them take over killing
the creature under the Security Treaty?
Our government and Self-Defense Forces
always have to take action first.
Even under our Treaty. it states the U.S.
can only provide support.
We're dealing with a living thing here.
We don't know what it'll do.
Irritating the creature could cause
even more damage.
Yes. it's a living thing.
Therefore. eradicating it should
be achievable.
Don't think of it like an earthquake
or typhoon.
because unlike a natural disaster.
we can stop it.
The citizens.
Shouldn't protecting them come first?
Prime Minster. we're aware that
this is a difficult decision.
yet in order to avoid the damage
from spreading.
your authorization is what's needed
right now.
You mean right now decide?
You're not serious?
There's no more time. Your decision.
The Prime Minister has just declared
the first ever national state of emergency
under the
Disaster Countermeasures Basic Act.
The SDF's being summoned to defend.
A first for Japan in reaction
to the Giant Unidentified Life-Form.
As an emergency measure. Diet approval
has officially been postponed.
For the first time since World War II.
the Prime Minister has issued an order
for the elimination of harmful creatures.
Nerima 1st Division has already
been dispatched at Tokyo's request.
Current operational units are tasked
with evacuation guidance
and rescue missions.
In any case.
they're not properly equipped for battle.
Attack helicopters are the way
to go for now.
We're still waiting on artillery.
- Find out about Kisarazu.
- Yes. sir.
Let's load the F-2s with incendiaries.
too. shall we?
No. Any collateral damage could affect
the very survival of the SDF.
We have to minimize the use of firepower.
We still don't know
what this thing's capable of.
I really think we need to be ready
to give it everything we've got.
I agree. Let's advocate for an integrated.
three-force operation
to the Joint Chiefs of Staff.
Call the Prime Minister.
They're proposing a joint task force with
the Eastern Army Commander as its leader.
And the objective is extermination.
The ground forces. they're prioritizing
evacuating residents and can't respond.
Our main force will be made up of rapid
response helicopters. is what we propose.
The city... this is an urban operation.
There's a possibility
elderly and ill citizens may remain.
Then I can't make any decisions
without checking the scene first.
Under these conditions.
we believe collateral damage.
including civilian casualties
and destruction of private property.
is unavoidable.
Prime Minister.
it's a difficult circumstance of course.
Nevertheless. we need your answer.
Understood.
This is a risky. unprecedented mission
against an unknown enemy.
Will anyone volunteer?
No. standard rotation.
This is what we signed up for.
every single one of us.
Attention! Salute!
13:08.
13:20. Over.
We can relax now.
Even a creature of that size.
the SDF will make short work of it.
Yeah. Hey. how about we see
if we can monetize the carcass
to help rebuild the city.
Minister. the old Imperial Army engaged
in wishful armchair theories.
Those ideas. I know are appealing.
but the fact of the matter is
that more than three million lives were
lost in the last war.
so I'm warning against
having unfounded optimism.
Hurry. hurry! Run!
Please watch your step! Remain calm!
Over here. this way! Let's go. quickly!
Local evacuation centers are useless
to us right now.
You got to tell us where
to send these people. Hurry!
The giant creature
appears to have suddenly stopped moving!
Stopped?
Why all of sudden?
Astounding.
My God. it's evolving.
Attacker 1. this is CP. Over.
CP. Attacker 1. Over.
Advance to holding area two.
Await further orders. Over.
Attacker 1. Roger.
The shape is different
from what was reported.
CP. Attacker 1.
The report was inaccurate.
I repeat. the report was inaccurate.
Attacker 1. CP.
Proceeding with the operation.
Stand by. Await instructions.
Evacuation of residents in
the operational area has concluded.
Understood.
Minister Hanamori.
we can open fire at any time now.
Then let's proceed.
We're ready. We'll fire on your command.
Say the word.
Very well.
Go ahead.
Attacker 1. CP.
Commence fire on the giant creature.
Commence fire.
I repeat. commence fire. Over.
CP. Attacker 1. Roger that. Firing.
Target in sight.
Aim straight for the head.
300.
Prepare to fire.
Hold your fire! Hold your fire!
Why aren't they doing anything?
Civilians spotted near the line of fire.
Standing by. please advise.
Civilians spotted!
Awaiting orders to fire!
Civilians in sight.
awaiting orders to fire.
Civilians in sight. awaiting orders
to fire.
There are civilians present.
Do we have permission to still open fire?
What do we do? Should we fire?
Your order?
Prime Minister!
Cancel the attack.
Protect the civilians.
None of them can be allowed to die
by our hand.
Attacker 1. CP. Abort attack.
To holding positions. Over.
Roger. Abort attack. Holding positions.
The Giant Unidentified Life-Form has
left Tennozu Canal!
It's broken through the expressway.
and is now moving
from the Keihin Canal to Tokyo Bay!
All flights in and out of Haneda Airport
have been canceled.
There's been a new fire outbreak
near the Shinagawa Ward
under the jurisdiction...
All Tokyo train service operation
has resumed...
Condolences and pledges of support
have been received...
The Tokyo Metropolitan Government's
Disaster Prevention Division is in need
- of more supplies and aid workers.
- The Tokyo Stock Exchange
has announced that it'll continue
trading as usual...
The Tokaido Shinkansen
is operating shuttle service
- from Shin-Yokohama Station.
- Academic research teams
from various countries.
including the United States and France.
have landed at Narita
and Kansai Airports...
The giant creature has yet to be spotted
in the Uraga Channel.
As a result. the Yokosuka Naval District
of the MSDF
has expanded the search area.
They're now searching in Sagami Bay.
The fires in both Ota Ward
and Shinagawa Ward have been put out.
A government inspection team led
by Disaster Management Minister Kanai
has been dispatched to directly survey
and assess the extent of the damage.
It was only on land for what.
a little over two hours?
And look at this devastation.
No.
Even though it was two hours.
our response was inadequate.
This is on us.
It was an unforeseen incident.
Out of our control.
We did the best we could.
given the circumstances. you know.
Just don't get cocky.
It's time to interview with the media.
Minister Kanai.
This way. please.
Okay. then.
Helm. all ahead. Full.
Aye. All ahead full.
Ensure strict anti-submarine
and surface vigilance.
We believe the Giant Unidentified
Life-Form has burrowed itself
into Tokyo Bay near Kanaya.
Currently. we've strengthened
our surveillance.
The MSDF is at work patrolling
the coast of Chiba as well Sagami Bay.
Though the Sagami Trough could
complicate things for us.
I doubt we could detect it in there.
So we don't know when
or where it will appear next?
What do we do if it comes on land again?
It'll be difficult to conduct a rapid land
strategy at the water's edge.
We might not be able
to respond immediately.
We need separate strategies
for a landing point encounter
and an expeditionary pursuit
so we can then use
first and second units accordingly.
Right. We'll draw up strategies
with coordinated artillery. tank.
and F-2 attacks in each and every scenario
for you to review.
Still. defensive operations are
heavily concentrated in the Kanto region.
Of course the metro area's defense
has to take top priority.
Yeah. Sounds like an order
from the fifth floor.
Does that mean they're just shelving
the other regions though?
Tokyo has just over 13 million residents.
GNP of 85 trillion yen.
which is 17% of the country's total.
The Kanto region. on the other hand.
200 trillion yen. 40% of the total.
It's a strategic decision intended
to safeguard the entire nation.
I guess protecting the country is hard.
We're leaving the defense plan
to headquarters
and setting up a special response team
in the PM's residence.
For the giant creature. right?
You were appointed as bureau chief.
or so I was told.
You got a promotion. Good for you.
Aren't you the one who assigns
all the team members?
Since you're friends
with all the bureaucrats.
Understood. I'll bring you some people
I can trust who won't mince their words.
Ah. Some people with balls.
- I'm Tachikawa.
- I'm Takeo.
- Ready. lift.
Everyone. my name is Rando Yaguchi.
No matter what you do in this office.
I assure you.
it won't affect your personnel evals.
So don't worry about job titles
or seniority within the ministries.
You should speak freely.
Well. there you have it.
I'll take over from here.
This is a gathering of people who
are outcasts of the bureaucracy.
Lone wolves. oddballs. nerds.
burdens. nuisances.
troublemakers and academic heretics.
We need you and your expertise.
so do what you do best.
These are the creature's essential specs.
Work together to find out what you can.
Wait. that's all?
Yes. that's all. So it's entirely up to us
to find the answer.
If anyone else has further information.
share it.
The experts yesterday couldn't
conclude anything.
And to our dismay.
nothing of value was gained.
all because they were at a loss
like the rest of us.
I've outlined all of the creature's
configurations so far.
Here's its first form.
its second form and its third form.
It seems like more mutations are coming.
More mutations?
Also. we at RIKEN are currently analyzing
the fluid samples
that were taken from the creature
the other day.
Send some over when you can because I can
get outside facilities to help us out.
Well. the U.S. already took the remaining
creature bodily fluid samples.
unfortunately.
Apparently. all the fluids left
at the scene were burned
on the pretext that they smelled
of rot and decay.
Uh-huh. that's right.
And I hear the Americans were the ones
who wanted that.
I'll leave the sample analysis
to RIKEN then.
What else? What do we have
in Behavioral Biology findings?
Only one behavioral pattern.
All it really does is relocate
so we can't determine
any sign of intellect.
And it's probably unlikely that it has
the ability to communicate with us.
I have a simple question.
What is its source of energy?
That's true.
It requires a gigantic amount of energy.
not just to get around but also
metabolically. now that I think about it.
Oxygen conversion
in its digestive tract alone
wouldn't be enough
for it to function properly.
All of that energy...
Is it nuclear fission?
You can't be serious. Ms. Ogashira?
Not possible.
The U.S. carrier is leaving port?
That's right.
The alert went off
at Yokosuka's radiation monitoring post
and we only received word of it just now.
I understand.
I'll check with
the Nuclear Regulation Authority.
Uh. yes. I have orders to refrain
from announcing it to the public.
however. an increase in radiation levels
has been observed all around Tokyo.
So does that mean
there was a leak somewhere?
Could it be a reactor?
No. We haven't found any leaks
of radioactive materials
at any of the nuclear facilities.
If that's the case.
then what's the source?
Is something like this
even possible?
Huh?
This survey data shows radiation spikes
that are identical
to the giant creature's path.
They're connected after all.
Look at this.
See?
Looks like what Ms. Ogashira
said was right.
I'm sorry.
The information has already spread
quite a lot throughout the general public.
Call Akasaka.
I'll head to the
Chief Cabinet Secretary's office now.
This is concerning.
That's why you or the Prime Minister
should hold a news conference immediately.
We haven't ID'd the radiation's source.
and. furthermore. the link to the
aforementioned organism remains unclear.
We'll stoke fear if we announce it now.
The radiation level isn't high enough
for us to issue an evacuation.
There are really no legal grounds for us
to act on this right now.
However. this is still a matter
involving radioactive material.
We should call a press conference.
You're right.
I'll see to it.
I'll talk to the Prime Minister.
A briefing.
Schedule a briefing with
the Prime Minister in five minutes.
Yes. President Ross.
I understand. Thank you.
So many requests from that country.
That's the U.S. for you.
An assistant deputy chief to the
U.S. President has secretly flown in.
He wants to have an unofficial meeting
with the Prime Minister.
Well. they certainly move fast.
Yeah. He's left Yokota Air Base already.
and he's on his way over here.
last I heard.
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs
is going crazy.
We've also received word
that his aide has made an appointment
to talk with you while she's here.
Me? Why's that?
I read your current administration data
and decided on you.
Your past is compelling.
and I figure you can be useful as well.
Rando Yaguchi's the best choice overall.
We're a great match.
Well. I actually think Akasaka.
the Prime Minister's aide.
would be better.
Honestly. he turned it down so I chose you.
I need something. and I need it
to look like I wasn't involved.
What I need is for you to find
this person in question.
Who are you trying to find?
Several years ago.
there was a person who literally predicted
your giant creature's sudden appearance.
I bet that piqued your interest.
The last update was that he landed
seven days ago in Narita.
Goro Maki.
Japanese.
Former college professor.
I hear your intelligence agency
is excellent.
so don't fail.
And what's in it for us?
I'll trade all our info
for whatever you know.
and then give you
our accumulated intelligence.
However. no leaking intelligence
to a third country.
Where's there a Zara?
Kayoco Anne Patterson.
She's very young.
That country values performance over age.
which is a great quality.
She's Senator Patterson's
eldest daughter as well.
The child of the senator behind
the Kern Agreement then.
She's a strong one.
Her success is thanks to a mixture
of talent. pedigree. and coattail-riding.
I'm guessing... she's not your type. huh?
No.
She has no shame.
She uses her father's connection
to get ahead.
She's just like Yaguchi.
a true politician.
You're looking for someone
at a time like this?
For Rando Yaguchi.
I owe a great debt to his father.
so prioritize this.
Assign however many agents you need.
This is all the info we have.
A heretical elderly professor
who was driven out of the country
and transferred to a U.S. institute.
Although a biologist.
it was an energy research institute
that he was transferred to.
Quite interesting. isn't it?
Is this a red notice?
No. Just locate his base of operations.
After that. the NSA or the CIA
will take over for us.
They told me
they'll get it done discreetly.
The last traces of the former professor.
As expected.
my grandma's country works fast.
Unfortunately. he's gone missing.
The Coast Guard found his little boat
adrift and unmanned
off the coast of Haneda.
Ms. Patterson.
Was it really Goro Maki
you were looking for. or was it this?
"I did what I wanted.
That means you should do the same."
Is this a suicide note?
Do you need me to confirm the contents?
Printed with special ink.
It can't be copied.
Then I'll take photos. They'll only be
shared with our response team.
"God... zilla"?
He chose to give it an English name.
"Gojira."
What's it mean?
Looks like there's only one result.
On Odo Island.
which was the guy's hometown.
it's a word that means "God incarnate."
A violent one.
I hear that's why he wanted "God"
included in the English name.
I don't like that.
Let's stick to the Japanese pronunciation.
Very well.
Gojira.
Who cares about the name right now?
It doesn't matter.
I think it's just as well
that it originated in the U.S.
The important thing is now it has a name.
Just now.
the government unofficially announced
that the giant creature will
be called Gojira.
According to our sources. "God incarnate"
is the meaning.
Goro Maki.
Former professor of integrative biology
at Jonan University.
I want you to find out
what kind of person he was.
We'll give it to you exclusively when
the time's right to go to print. Hayafune.
That's a promise.
I'll let you know
when we're ready for you.
Yeah.
I know you will.
60 years ago.
These are documents on the unregulated
dumping of radioactive waste in the ocean.
Don't tell me...
Gojira fed on these?
That was the DOE's conclusion.
The DOE noticed organisms that fed on
radioactive waste.
and asked various institutions
to analyze them.
Former professor Maki was the main figure
in all this.
The radioactive waste was dumped in the
middle of an active marine life habitat.
An organism from ancient times
that had miraculously survived.
It didn't die out
due to radiation exposure.
Instead. the organism evolved
to have radiation resistance.
That was his theory for Godzilla.
However. Ms. Patterson.
the Gojira that arrived on land is clearly
longer than what was estimated.
It has to do with its ability
to change
from an aquatic to a terrestrial creature.
It's beyond all of this info
that the DOE's given us.
and I can't explain it either.
I've officially told you everything
that I have the authority to know.
So what now?
- Hey!
- Huh?
- So these were Professor Maki's then?
I can't make sense of it.
Well. it's definitely
not molecular geometry.
How does it relate to Gojira?
It's outside my field.
so I don't really understand it.
but maybe an analytical table
of structural layers.
It's missing data
that was intentionally left out
so that no one who found it
could accurately analyze it.
If we combine that with this.
we'll have the complete version.
Do you mind if we analyze it as well?
- Is that okay?
I'm not really great
with Japanese formality.
so can we speak casually?
Then answer this.
What does the U.S. want with Gojira?
Will they study it or exterminate it?
What are they planning?
The one who decides that is the President.
Who decides in your country?
The Cabinet has finally decided
on a bill for relief and recovery?
The Gojira-related bill is also difficult
to coordinate between the ministries.
Orders are clouded right now since
it's such an unprecedented case.
It's not exactly a shock that no one wants
to take responsibility right now.
The bill on confidential info.
It passed easily at least. Yeah?
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs forced it.
pressured by the U.S.. as usual.
There's value in holding
all the knowledge. after all.
U.S. wants to use its Gojira intel
as a diplomatic card in the future.
We'll have to rely on Akasaka.
He's crafty and good at negotiating.
he can handle the White House.
Here are the analysis results
of the radioactive material
recovered at the scene.
The wavelength of these gamma rays
doesn't match those of existing ones.
It's a huge discovery.
Uh. Gojira. was it?
There's a new. unknown element inside
of its body. that's what this means.
So this is why the U.S.
and their Department of Energy
took such quick action. huh?
- Let's take this data with us.
- O-okay.
- Call the Prime Minister.
- Sir.
I understand.
Radioactivity makes things
more complicated.
So...
how much do we say?
As a result of having fully
analyzed samples
that were recovered
from along the path of Gojira.
we were able to detect radiation
of 0.5 microsieverts in the area.
Thank you for the food.
- Thank you for the food.
- Thanks.
However. even though the U.S. gave us
all their information.
now we're at a dead end.
It feels like we're at a dead end
in several ways.
I agree. although RIKEN's data
was impactful. after all.
I never thought Gojira would have eight
times the genetic information of humans.
We don't even know the number of years it
would take to sequence all of that info.
This only verifies our suspicion
that Gojira's the most evolved creature
on the entire planet.
It doesn't evolve generationally.
It self-mutates as a single individual.
Perfection that exceeds even humans.
Gojira's still a living thing.
That means we can kill it.
Well. that's our aim.
Don't forget why we're all gathered here.
to find out how to defeat it.
Has anyone found any clues into
its behavior while we're here?
The only thing it does is walk.
It went back to Tokyo Bay suddenly.
Why do we think it decided to do that?
I get it.
To cool itself.
Gojira likely has
a nuclear reactor-like system inside it.
and from the dorsal fin.
the heat is released.
However. that isn't enough on its own.
The main way that Gojira cools itself
is through using blood flow. That's it.
So it evolved to a sea creature in an
effort to regulate its body temperature...
it couldn't cool as well when
it was the land creature it mutated into.
is what you mean.
Sounds like our only hope is to keep it
from regulating its temperature.
Shut down its internal cooling system.
If it's shut down.
Gojira will have no choice
but to put its reactor into a scram state
to stay alive.
This process of rapid cooling could freeze
its activity for a little while.
but we have no idea if it will be enough
to kill it once and for all.
What about the possibility
of orally administering
a blood coagulation promoter
for this purpose.
It's in an upright walking form.
Can it be done?
We'll work out all the details
and create the best strategy.
Just looking at it though.
maybe a pump truck could do the job.
We. the Ministry of Health and METI
can be in charge of gathering tools.
coagulant.
and special vehicles
from all over the country.
Take this to the Prime Minister
immediately.
and call it the "Yaguchi Plan."
Understood.
However it's named. let's submit it.
Gojira deserves to live! Gojira is a god!
Gojira deserves to live!
Gojira is a god!
Thank you for your hard work.
Oh. Thank you. as always.
Thank you very much.
Everyone. Let's take a break.
I see everyone here doing all they can
without even being asked.
Even though we tell them to go home
and rest.
or see their families.
they choose not to go home.
Or if they do. they return
with home-cooked meals for everyone.
It's very encouraging sir.
With the preparation
of the Gojira-related bills
and Deputy Chairman Izumi's coordination.
each ministry's working together
regardless of jurisdiction.
A lot of outsiders from other departments
have also been working tirelessly
because they volunteered to help us.
You're right.
This country has much to offer.
That's how I feel.
If I may ask a question though.
How long ago did you last change
your shirt?
Hmm?
Honestly. it's making the room stink a bit.
Really?
If you're asking my opinion.
a shower would be best.
Mr. Yaguchi.
It appeared again
in Sagami Bay seconds ago.
It's making its way to Kamakura.
Activate J-Alert.
Transmit a warning of Gojira's arrival
at the shore.
Prepare for transmission
of the primary alert over Em-Net.
This is Kamakura Disaster Prevention.
This is an evacuation
issued by the government.
A Giant Unidentified Life-Form
has come ashore.
An emergency evacuation order
has been issued.
All citizens.
follow the instructions of the police.
The Prime Minister.
The target is passing through
Kamakura. and advancing toward Kamariya.
Wait. It's gotten a lot larger
since the first landing.
Yeah. Beyond what we had theorized.
Even its face and body are different. too.
Yes. It looks to be nearly
double the size.
Gojira has evolved.
This would be his fourth form.
It'll leave a trail of destruction
in its wake.
Residents outside the affected area.
take refuge indoors!
Going out without permission
is prohibited by law!
You are in a designated evacuation zone!
Attention. citizens!
There's a high probability
that Gojira will reach Tokyo
within three hours.
Why's it coming over here again?
As stated in the handout here.
a direct assault on its body
runs the risk of releasing radioactive
material into the environment.
But we can't allow the capital
to be overrun again.
so we think the top priority
should be preventing its attack.
Radioactive material is the creature's
primary energy source.
Just imagine if it attacked
one of our nuclear facilities.
That would be a bigger disaster.
Prime Minister. we have to strike.
And right away.
Prime Minister. we want to avoid
a situation where we're seen as weak
or timid by the rest of the world.
What of the Yaguchi Plan.
what's the current status?
Unfortunately.
it's not ready to be put into action.
Just give the order. and the SDF will do
its job. even in the urban areas.
The declared state of emergency
is still in effect.
The Prime Minister can order the attack.
and that attack has to be decided
by the Prime Minister.
Your call.
I understand.
I authorize it.
Yes. Prime Minister.
Contact command.
Yes.
The Prime Minister has ordered
the implementation of a new operation.
We have unlimited weapon use.
is that clear?
The Minister of Defense has told us
to do whatever it takes.
We need to get rid of Gojira
before it reaches Tokyo.
If it lands on Kanagawa.
we'll go with Operation B.
Good. Activate B-2 with Kawasaki
as the primary battleground
for the extermination.
Roger that. The Tama River's the absolute
defense line in the case of B-2.
Operation Taba's a go.
Attacker formation
will report five miles west.
PO304. taking off from Tachikawa: 15:36.
Tank and artillery battalions
being deployed at Maruko Bridge.
Roger. Prepare to fire.
This has to succeed.
Eight minutes until
expected time of encounter.
So we're really engaging in live fire?
Relax. Do what you were trained to do.
The target has radioactive material
in its body.
Therefore. we'll only pinpoint our attacks
on the head and legs.
I want all units to be aware of this.
Target approaching. Three minutes
until expected time of encounter.
1st to 4th anti-helicopter platoons.
arriving shortly.
CO1. this is CP. Over.
CP. CO1. Over.
CO1. CP.
PO1 in flight over Musashi-Kosugi Station.
holding at BP1.
PO2 to PO4 behind the towers.
Standby at holding area two. Over.
CP. CO1. BP approaching.
Target Distance. 1.200 meters. Over.
Roger that. Maintain positions. Over.
Preparation for helicopter
reconnaissance. completed.
Total area evacuation is also completed.
Koriyama. are you entirely sure
there are no stragglers?
We just have to believe the reports
from the field.
The target is still advancing.
Prime Minister.
please authorize the use of weapons.
Weapons are authorized... from here on.
We've confirmed
the Prime Minister's order.
We can commence firing. Authorize it.
Taba Operation Phase One commence.
We are all clear to open fire now.
We are clear to fire. Over.
CP. CO1. Roger. Firing.
Ready. Fire.
Autocannon.
All rounds. direct hits. Ineffective.
Apache 30-millimeter ready.
Let's see what that does.
Ninja ACP.
Third wave of reconnaissance in progress.
Report results.
3rd Squadron engaged.
Target fine. Weapons had no effect.
16.000 rounds of machine-gun fire later...
and not even a single scratch.
Contact headquarters and the PM.
The Eastern Army Commander is requesting
permission to use guided missiles.
It's a dense area. but we have no choice.
I strongly urge you to grant permission.
Unlimited weapon use...
Is officially authorized.
Do what you must.
CO1. CP.
Switch assault to guided missiles.
As soon as preparations are complete.
fire them all! Over.
Roger that.
PO1 to PO4. fire all guided missiles!
Giant creature straight ahead.
700.
Prepare to fire. Fire!
TOW. Hellfire. Fire all rounds!
"All direct hits yet no visible
or clear damage to the creature."
End of the report.
The missiles aren't even hurting it.
What the hell is that?!
The outer shell is harder to pierce
than we had expected.
We'll shift the operation to Phase Two.
Tiger 1. CP.
Taba Operation Phase Two commence.
You are clear to fire.
I repeat. You are clear to fire. Over.
Roger that. Tiger.
This is Tiger 1.
Commence fire. Commence fire.
Type 10 tanks. Target ahead.
Aim for its legs.
Anti-tank concentrated barrage.
Give orders!
All vehicles. Loaded. Ready to fire.
Distance good. Fire!
Direct hit. Continue to fire!
The target. its speed appears
to have decreased!
Good. Let's keep pushing then.
Layer on some artillery fire.
Time on target. ten. eight. seven.
six. five. four. three...
Impact now.
All shells hit the target!
Fusillade. Fire!
Target has crossed the levee
and is now entering the Tama River!
Inform Gotemba and Special Forces.
Commence attack.
The target has halted!
It's time to shift to Phase Three now.
Start the aerial assault right away.
Type 10 tanks. This is 10.
Move to Phase Three.
All vehicles to new positions!
I repeat. all vehicles to new positions!
The target is changing course
to northwest.
I repeat. changing course to northwest!
Why's it turning away?
Does that mean the airstrike's working?
JDAM second wave incoming.
Good. this will certainly finish it.
We did it.
All vehicles evacuate!
Evacuate! Evacuate!
Evacuate!
Target's crossed the Tama River
and is now entering Tokyo!
ACP. CO1.
All aircraft. all weapons.
out of munitions.
I repeat. all weapons. out of munitions.
Tiger 1. This is 40.
Visibility zero. Target unconfirmed.
CP. This is Tiger 1.
The 8th platoon is out of munitions.
Three tanks are severely damaged.
two are moderately damaged. Over.
Forward command post destroyed.
Taba Combat Group loses command.
Target's breached the defense line.
Defensive position has collapsed.
Operation cannot continue.
Joint Staff Vice Chief.
the creature's still within
artillery range.
We need to continue the offense.
We can't. We haven't received word
on the evacuation in Ota and Setagaya.
Ah! We're sorry.
We're afraid this is all we can do.
Understood.
Operation suspended.
We couldn't hold it back.
It's disappointing.
Don't let it discourage you.
Our job is to protect the people first.
Attacking isn't the only way.
Speed up the evacuations.
Operation Taba has failed.
Gojira's unscathed. It's relocating again.
The Self-Defense Forces' full power
was futile.
Its ability to defend itself
exceeded our calculations.
If we could just defeat it
using physical weapons.
we wouldn't be here struggling so much.
Is it really a perfect creature
beyond human understanding?
Target's moving from Setagaya Ward
to Meguro Ward.
Prime Minister.
let's petition the U.S. troops in Japan
to cooperate
in the creature's extermination.
Prime Minister. from the U.S. Ambassador.
U.S. Air Force bombers have already
taken off from Guam.
They're on their way now.
Submit a formal cooperation request
to the U.S. quickly.
I'll find the ambassador
at Yokota and get authorization.
I suggest holding
an emergency news conference
regarding the U.S. forces in Japan.
We've requested that
the U.S. military assist us.
They'll cooperate
in the extermination of Gojira
under the Japan-U.S Security Treaty.
This is the bombing zone
proposed by the U.S.
The area will be this wide?
This is crazy.
This is even worse than Gojira.
We can't transport them all.
Evacuate citizens
to underground structures.
The U.S. military will begin launching
their attack on Gojira!
For your safety. go underground!
Evacuate to subways and underground malls!
Calm down! Yes!
Don't push!
This location is located
directly in Gojira's path.
Our Self-Defense Forces
couldn't eradicate it.
It's likely that the U.S. forces
will also fail.
What are you saying?
You really want us to evacuate?
Yes!
Ichigaya and Ariake are dangerous. too!
We have to leave as soon as we can.
We'll transfer the functions of
the Prime Minister's office to Tachikawa.
They're about to start their airstrike
at Tokyo in any minute.
My duty is to stay here.
We all have a duty
to keep track of this mission.
We can't abandon our citizens.
We can't run away in the face of danger!
Prime Minister.
As our leader. it's your duty to protect
the nation and its people.
even if that means abandoning Tokyo.
so I urge you to leave.
Fortunately.
the Tokyo government's still functioning.
So what we should do is leave
Governor Kozuka in command just for now.
Very well.
We'll prepare two helicopters
from Kisarazu.
Sir. I'll travel with my team by car.
All right then. Go ahead.
That is going to take some time.
The traffic will be horrendous.
We'll see you there.
Yes. I will make sure of it.
A mandatory evacuation order
has been issued
due to the approach of a giant creature!
Everyone please evacuate at once!
A mandatory evacuation order
has been issued
due to the approach of a giant creature!
Everyone please evacuate at once!
Go. go! Let's go! Come on!
Everywhere is gridlocked like this.
We're not going anywhere.
Looks like it.
The military will attack soon.
We need to get everyone underground.
So that's Gojira.
Deputy Chief. the U.S. airstrike is
starting earlier than originally planned.
The target sustained damage
from both of the MOP II bombs.
Bleeding confirmed. A successful strike.
Finally.
Way to go. U.S.A.
Prime Minister. the helicopters
will arrive any minute.
- Over here. everyone. down the stairs!
- Remain calm!
- Underground!
- What's that light?
The organ that controls heat on its back
has started glowing all of a sudden!
We have no further details!
What's it doing now?
I don't see anybody else.
Come on. let's get inside.
The name truly suits it.
Taking off 18:35.
Transporting the Prime Minister
and eight others...
High levels of radiation
are to be expected.
All Tokyo residents are urged
to remain indoors for at least 49 hours...
Just how much radioactive material
did Gojira release on Tokyo?
The radiation exposure caused
by the giant unknown creature...
Don't rely on the government.
There's a confirmed hot spot over there.
The radiation levels in the air are high.
Should we distribute the stable
iodine tablets we have in stock.
or should we use them immediately?
Fire and Rescue Mobile Units. from
the 3rd and 9th Regional headquarters...
There's a risk of a secondary disaster.
...have been dispatched
for decontamination and rescue
within the Tokyo metropolitan area.
The safety of Prime Minister Okouchi.
Chief Cabinet Secretary Azuma.
and the five other people scheduled
to become acting Prime Ministers
are all unknown.
The Metropolitan Police Department.
the MLIT. and the MIC...
We need to restore
the telephone lines ASAP.
Combine our dedicated lines.
public lines and private lines.
There's no prospect of any infrastructure
in the affected areas being restored.
Going forward we will need
to consider moving the capital
to Saitama New Urban Center.
Sapporo. Fukuoka...
We're unable to contact a significant
number of embassies in Japan...
A huge number of evacuees...
Foreigners living in Japan are being
advised by their home countries
to leave Japan and return home
on chartered flights...
In order to avoid a political vacuum.
several cabinet ministers
who have been contacted are currently
in discussions with ruling party officials
to select an acting Prime Minister.
With the Prime Minister's
residence in danger.
federal headquarters
have officially relocated
to the Tachikawa-wide Area
Disaster Prevention Base.
which was established as a temporary base
in the event of an emergency.
This is a notice to all visitors
of the Tachikawa Disaster Prevention
Joint Government Building.
- Deputy Chief Yaguchi.
- I'll call you later.
Mr. Izumi.
Well. I'm glad you're safe.
It was a good thing
that I visited home on Friday.
You should think of visiting
your hometown. too.
Hey. You look like you're injured.
You okay?
I'm sorry. First aid supplies
are out of stock everywhere.
I'm fine. It's nothing serious.
Fire department personnel
should follow
the Tokyo Metropolitan Government.
Let the police
take care of the homeless refugees.
They won't die
if you leave them overnight!
The affected population
is estimated to be three million.
We need to get a jump on the press.
All right. I need to hear
the latest intel.
What's the situation?
All we can say is it's still inactive.
We're not sure why it suddenly stopped.
but it's near Tokyo Station.
Current radiation levels?
The Nuclear Regulation Authority
is still taking readings.
They're busy surveying
the whole metro area.
Gojira's still releasing trace amounts
of radioactive material
from its mouth. however.
this level won't be an issue.
Gojira's plume has drifted out to sea.
and yet. we're looking at a wide area
of contamination.
The three wards in Tokyo that were hit
directly may be uninhabitable.
Decontamination could be an issue.
The situation is extremely serious.
life-or-death.
But we don't have nearly enough manpower
or supplies or even legal infrastructure.
There was nothing we could do.
The Prime Minister. Minister Hanamori.
the Chief Cabinet Secretary...
I'm afraid all of them are dead.
Don't rely on those who aren't here!
Those who remain now.
we just need to do what we can!
Yaguchi.
- I regret to report that
their deaths have now been confirmed.
- You need to calm yourself down.
Prime Minister Okouchi
and 11 other Cabinet members.
including Foreign Affairs
Minister Kunihira.
Minister of Health.
Labor and Welfare Iwata.
- Good.
- and Chief Cabinet Secretary Azuma
were among them.
Surviving cabinet ministers are in
discussions with ruling party officials
to select an acting Prime Minister
in an effort...
I'm sorry.
And there is still a risk
of a secondary disaster.
So who's the acting Prime Minister
right now?
The ruling party has reached a decision.
The Minister of Agriculture. Forestry
and Fisheries. Yusuke Satomi.
has been appointed acting Prime Minister.
This emergency measure is to ensure
the government continues to function
and to avoid a political vacuum.
Regardless. he's not only
received the Prime Minister's Award.
he also has the clear advantage
of factional seniority.
Look where he is now...
he's the Prime Minister.
I hear it was the Secretary General
and the rest of the ministers
who forced it on him.
Think of it this way.
In times like these.
no one wants to take responsibility.
From Sasebo. there's some disturbing
activity off the coast of Tsushima.
Very well.
I suppose we'll just have to wait and see.
Can the Minister of Foreign Affair
take action?
We're working to restore it
as we speak. It'll be soon.
I see.
Then try to avoid
any unforeseen circumstances.
Yes. I'll be sure to convey that
to the ambassador.
Ah. My noodles got soggy.
Turns out being Prime Minister
is a lot harder than I thought.
Yeah. he's a difficult man to read.
Whoever the Prime Minister is.
it's our duty to support the country.
We need to draft
the emergency legislation.
However. 30 kilometers away.
Gojira's currently resting.
You're not worried?
No need to worry about a political vacuum
if we're attacked over here.
If I've learned anything.
it's that one of Japan's strengths
is deciding its next leader quickly.
Does that mean you're next?
No way.
Perhaps in ten years though.
Well. if Japan's still around
in ten years.
you should definitely run for office.
You'll get my vote.
I'll take Secretary General in exchange.
I heard that Akasaka was safe since
he was at Yokota before it all went down.
A politician needs strategy.
and good luck as well.
Now he's acting Chief Cabinet Secretary.
just look at him.
Why can't you be more like that.
Play the game.
You're Minister for Special Missions
and Deputy Director.
That's unique.
You're the de facto executive officer now.
It sounds nice. but I'll be the one
to take the fall if we fail.
That's Akasaka's clever strategy.
You'll be selected as the new aide
to the Prime Minister.
That's the position you want. isn't it?
What's wrong with advancing your career?
Why'd you become a politician.
if you're not into that?
'Cause you always know
who your friends are.
It's simple. That's why I like it.
Deputy Director.
Bureau members have arrived.
More than half of our team survived.
I'm grateful that you're all here
in light of this recent tragedy.
Thank you.
Our hearts are heavy for those who.
unfortunately. didn't make it.
We have to do our best on behalf of them.
And we must keep moving forward.
The sadness of losing loved ones
and colleagues.
I'm sorry to say. never truly goes away.
However. we can all prevail.
So. for the sake of the people.
I ask you to pour your heart and souls
into finishing our work here.
I beg you.
Let's all get back to work.
- Chief Mori.
- Yes.
What's the update on the freezing plan?
Due to a lack of data.
private companies are working separately
to create around 24 different
prototypes of blood clotting promoters
using silica. thrombin and other agents.
One of these ought to work on Gojira.
How can we verify that?
We've already asked the GSDF to collect
biological cells
and we'll use those samples
to narrow it down.
Roger that.
The samples were collected. sir.
Then we'll go ahead and send them
to BSL-4 labs in Tsukuba immediately.
Understood.
Send all of the remaining samples
to a P3-level facility.
whether public or private.
However. these are classified substances.
so that's a bad idea.
It's all right. We need as much info
on Gojira as we can get.
No change to the radiation levels
in the air.
It's stable at around 0.8 to 1 sievert.
He's a quiet sleeper.
Well. then. that means
it's storing it all up in its stomach.
Shift change. Fall back.
This is Yaguchi.
We're arriving in five.
Can you secure us a meeting
with the acting Prime Minister?
To be clear. you'd like to provide us with
knowledge from the United States
to assist in our fight?
A U.S.-Japan Gojira research coalition?
It'll be all right.
The more knowledge. the better.
Let's clear some space for them.
Footage from the GSDF's latest unmanned
reconnaissance aircraft system.
After the attack. it immediately froze.
It seems Gojira froze immediately
after the attack. like the simulation.
Same as the D2 simulation.
So It's safe to assume
that all approaching flying objects
will be instinctively intercepted.
Squad 2. this is CV1.
Five minutes from point zero.
Ten minutes remaining. Over.
CV1. Squad 2. Roger that.
We've cross-referenced field data
with the data from Tsukuba.
and it's possible that Gojira
will reproduce asexually.
We anticipate the number of individuals
to grow exponentially around the world.
From an evolutionary view.
they could reduce in size
and then sprout wings and spread globally.
In Washington. the Secretary of Defense
is arguing that...
He wants to dispose of Godzilla
with a thermonuclear weapon.
And what's the take from the White House?
A report shown to the President
said there's a 13% chance
that Godzilla will land on the West Coast.
Allegedly. the UN ambassador
is setting up a multinational
Godzilla strike force
with the Security Council.
Will the U.S. go through with it?
Looks like it.
Yokota and the U.S. team have concluded
that the only option is a nuclear attack
using ballistic missiles.
Apparently. it's started.
The Pentagon's already working
on setting the explosive yield
for a B83 nuclear warhead.
They're planning on using it on Tokyo?
I was ordered to evacuate right away.
Hold on.
So you're saying it's decided?
But I'm not gonna do that.
My grandmother lived through
two atomic bombs.
I refuse to witness a third bomb dropped
on her country.
I won't let it happen.
Certainly. yes.
Then we'll go ahead and act accordingly.
President Ross.
Well. you heard it.
That country really does force
some unreasonable demands on us.
This is too much.
How can we stand for this?!
I agree.
Call the Chief Cabinet Secretary.
Right.
The UN Security Council passed
a resolution to form a multinational force
centered on the U.S. military...
to exterminate Gojira once and for all.
As party to the resolution
and participant.
the Japanese nation will be under
their command.
In other words...
...I am going to need special legislation
delegating full authority
to the Prime Minister.
This legislation...
it'll also authorize the use
of a nuclear weapon?
I didn't want this.
This'll be how I go down in history.
From here on. the U.S. will be
in charge of exterminating Gojira.
under UN jurisdiction.
After the war.
Japan became a tributary state.
The postwar period will continue forever.
You're just giving up then?
A direct hit from a thermonuclear weapon.
No living creature could possibly
withstand that million-degree heat.
If we want to completely eradicate it
then a nuclear attack is the right choice.
But we're on the verge of a breakthrough
with our freezing method.
Please reconsider.
But your plan has too many unknowns
at the end of the day.
Besides. if we move forward
with the nuclear attack.
the countries from around the world have
already pledged their support
to assist us
in the nation's reconstruction.
If we can't completely dispose of Gojira
while the world is looking to us.
then we risk our nation losing
their trust for good.
We have no choice
but to rely on this nuclear attack.
You know what my job is?
To look to the future.
To consider what will happen
to our country after Gojira is eradicated.
The damage has only affected
three wards so far.
meaning Tokyo can still be rebuilt.
Using nuclear weapons
will make that difficult.
The city's economy is already
virtually nonexistent.
With bond and stock prices
continuing to plummet.
and the yen weakening as we speak.
rebuilding will be impossible
if the nation defaults.
You don't realize. that what we need
is international funding and sympathy
to survive.
So your first priority is reconstruction?
To save the country.
We have to do whatever it takes.
Yaguchi...
wake up.
This is our reality.
Did you say a nuclear attack on Gojira?
Their bombing our country?!
The government just approved it
and they already notified the UN.
But that's insane.
Gojira has transcended evolution.
How do we know it hasn't
conquered death itself?
So the only two ways to end this
is Yaguchi Plan's coagulation
or incinerate it with a nuke.
While it's true that we could choose
to use the nuke...
that doesn't mean we should.
Who's the real threat to us.
man or Gojira?
The UN will want to begin
the nuclear attack right away.
However. they'll likely evacuate
all the Tokyo residents first.
That gives us our window
for finishing our work here.
That's right.
Through the sample experiments.
we were able to determine
the most effective substance.
Now comes production.
Based on the estimated
blood volume of Gojira.
we'll need at least 672 kiloliters
of coagulant.
We're securing plants nationwide
for production.
Will we make it?
Of course we'll make it! We have to!
Don't give up now!
Don't abandon our country
when we still have time!
As many production lines as we can get.
We need every private chemical company
across the country on this.
If anyone can get it done. you can.
I'll send over all the pertinent data
to your researcher.
so ask the director to send a
simplified draft of the production process
as soon as they can.
Thanks to the samples
being scattered around.
we're getting broad cross-checking.
Interesting. sharing our data worked.
Please have the police and MLIT
work out the logistics
for the local transport of coagulants.
Okay. I'll get on that.
And in return. I need the METI
to coordinate pump makers.
A company in Shanghai's willing
to give us three tankers.
Just as long as we agree
to give them back when we're finished.
That's not a concern. We just need five
wheel loaders. it doesn't matter the size.
Ambassador Lansing has informed us
of the multinational forces estimate
on the amount of energy Gojira released
during the last battle.
They project the creature's energy beam
will be back to full power
within 360 hours.
In other words. it's likely Gojira's
activity will resume in 15 days.
I see.
Evacuation.
That means forcing residents to abandon
everything they've ever known.
This isn't an easy decision.
I agree. sir.
Evacuate 3.6 million citizens.
It's impossible.
Even the police can't carry out
an operation on that scale.
Not only Tokyo. but Chiba and Kanagawa
are also affected.
Too many residents are involved here.
Governor Kozuka strongly protests
the sacrifice of Tokyo.
This is an important national decision.
It isn't a municipal one.
Relocation selection and approvals
won't be completed in time.
Two weeks isn't enough.
The moment that Gojira resumes
activity again
is the moment that the thermonuclear
attack will be moved up unconditionally.
Casualties will be unavoidable.
I'm afraid.
because. at that time.
ballistic missiles will be launched
from a strategic nuclear submarine at us.
as per the decision
of the international coalition.
Damn it!
Yeah. easy for them to say
since we're all the way over in Asia!
If it were in New York.
they'd do the same thing.
Their decision was made
regardless of where we are.
Children come first!
Parents. please don't let go
of your children's hands at any time!
Hey. where are we going?
Land prices in western Japan are soaring.
And food's in short supply.
Companies and shops
in the Kanto area are shuttered.
City's full of unemployed citizens.
The yen's also continuing to weaken.
reflecting investors' fears.
Well. some people are profiting from it.
There are all kinds of individuals.
in this world.
You got any information that's not online?
Of course. It's what I do. after all.
In exchange for this.
I need you to promise one thing.
Print my article one day before
the nuclear attack.
I have new info on Gojira.
In exchange. the announcement timing
is for us to decide.
How's that sound?
Yeah. yeah. I get it.
It seems the professor resented
the radiation sickness
that ultimately took his wife's life.
So that's why he continued his research
into neutralizing radioactive material.
If it's possible to neutralize
radioactive material.
it's also possible to create
new radioactive material.
He must have feared
that it would be used by the military.
That would explain why he chose to redact
so much of the DOE data.
He hated radioactive material.
And he probably hated anyone
who was involved in its creation.
Japan left his wife to die.
so it was no exception.
And yet. he purposefully left behind
his data and wrote. "Do as you like."
What a strange person.
So what did he end up choosing to do?
Thank you for the meal.
Any luck on solving the chart?
Not even with help from
the encryption specialist department
over at Intelligence and Research.
Are there any updates from the U.S.?
Haven't heard anything concrete so far.
It's best not to rely on them.
We regard it as significant data
for some kind of multitiered approach
related to Gojira.
yet there's still more to it.
Rather than a chemical schematic.
it looks more like a conceptual pattern.
or mandala.
It's a paradoxical question
that can't be solved
unless you can imagine the answer first.
Professor Maki was a little twisted.
Even I don't get the meaning
of these lines.
Why'd he put it on paper and not data.
is my question.
Well. perhaps it should be folded.
You know. Gojira's so huge.
it doesn't look like it could fill up
on radioactive waste.
I bet it's always hungry.
No doubt.
And what's funny
is that its teeth are all misaligned.
You wouldn't think it could eat
nuclear waste like this.
Origami.
The waste isn't eaten.
By folding the paper
into two origami shapes.
new information is revealed to us
and we're able to grasp
the entire pattern.
As a result...
We were too fixated on radioactive
material being the energy source.
What Professor Maki left behind.
is a molecular chart
for converting elements in the body.
Element conversion molecules.
The unknown radioactive isotope
detected earlier.
its very existence. that's the proof.
Substances with few protons.
such as hydrogen or nitrogen.
are passed through the cell membrane
to convert the elements inside the cell
into the necessary molecules.
We can assume that Gojira is a mixotroph
with a thermonuclear energy conversion
organ that uses the heat from the decay.
It's a bold theory but within reason.
It can live anywhere as long
as there's water and oxygen.
Like an ascetic surviving on mist.
To sum it all up. Gojira's a threat
to humanity's existence
yet also poses a revelation of infinite
physical possibilities all at once.
Did I get that right?
But then we're facing the possibility
that the blood coagulant
will be neutralized in its body
and therefore prove to be ineffective.
The Yaguchi Plan could fall through.
If that's the case. what should we do?
We raise its certainty of working.
The Yaguchi Plan is all we have.
after all.
First of all. we have to analyze
this molecular structure
and find a way around it.
Ready for the analysis?
Supercomputers all over Japan have already
started running parallel analysis
under our initiative. however. how many
days will it take to get the results?
We only have ten days left
before the nuclear attack.
That's why I asked the MEXT to use
their global connections on our behalf.
We've received a call from Japan.
They're asking to connect
our supercomputers
in parallel to help analyze Godzilla.
Under no circumstances can we do that.
If we open up our closed system
to foreign countries.
we might as well publish
our research data online.
We should tell them that we're
very sorry. but our hands are tied here.
Oh. just take a deep breath and calm down.
I think we can have faith in the Japanese.
don't you? Hmm?
Go ahead and tell them we'd be happy
to support them at this time.
- We've solved Professor Maki's riddle!
- Huh?
Oh. Let me see.
- What?
- Let me see. let me see. let me see.
Here.
Hey. wait. wait.
Extraordinary.
As you can see.
It's not the cell membrane itself.
It's actually the molecular structure
of an extremophile
that inhibits the activity
of the cell membrane.
If we also administer this inhibitor. it
could ensure the success of the coagulant.
Freezing Gojira's possible. after all.
Looks promising.
Okay.
Professor Maki likely anticipated
all of this.
He may have wanted to unleash the power
of a raging god as some kind of test.
To test humanity. this country
and the Japanese people.
His note said to do whatever we want. and
that includes the use of nuclear weapons.
That's right.
He did say to do what we want.
But still...
getting your way in this country
is difficult.
You're right.
Especially alone.
Here's the latest.
It sounds like the last kinks
in the Yaguchi Plan are being ironed out
even as we speak.
I'd like to once again
ask for your approval to deploy it.
I understand. Izumi.
but a UN resolution
has already been passed.
Some say that the U.S. is trying
to bring this to an early close
in order to obscure the fact that they've
been concealing Gojira's existence.
We're already well aware of all of that.
You understand our country's
current position. don't you?
Of course I do.
Saving another country from embarrassment
shouldn't come at the cost of our country.
So what you're saying is we should honor
the principle of human rights.
Prime Minister.
perhaps we should start doing
what we want to do.
You're right.
So. where do I. uh. put my stamp?
The purpose is to freeze the activity
of the Giant Unidentified Life-Form.
Operational guidelines centered on the
oral administration of a blood coagulant.
It's long-winded
This is the government. after all.
It's childish to call it
the Gojira Freezing Operation.
Why not Operation Yashiori?
Make it so.
This will be carried out in five stages.
Asaka has worked out the details already.
Remote vehicle operation training.
restoration of
the overhead infrastructure.
and explosive drills
have all been completed.
All that's left is execution.
Thank you all very much.
No need to thank us.
This is our work.
Only two days left on the countdown.
Ah. damn it.
It'll take another three days
to secure the production
of the minimum amount of inhibitor.
Is there any way we can suspend
the 24-hour countdown?
Then we have to think of how
we can delay the Security Council.
Who can help us stall?
China and Russia are out...
they're pushing for the attack.
They're too close geopolitically.
What about France?
They're a nuclear power.
I think they'd be interested
in Gojira's biology.
Hmm. right.
I have connections over there.
Let me reach out to them.
Yes. please.
I'll also contact
the European Bureau Chief.
That'd be great.
I'll talk to Foreign Minister Katayama.
Secure 24 more hours at all costs.
Understood.
A joint operation with the U.S. military?
The success rate will be higher
than if the SDF acted alone.
What about each side's command units.
will they be able to coordinate that?
This country's well-liked. you know.
It already looks like you'll get support
from the Marines and the Air Force.
We've even secured extra drones.
if you need 'em.
So. what do you say?
I'm in.
We've scraped together the minimum amount
of inhibitor somehow.
That's right.
Please send some tankers to SB in Tsukuba
as soon as possible.
All of the necessary materials and
coagulant are ready to be transported
for the start of the operation.
Go ahead and give the green light to HQ.
Deputy Chief
I urge you to please reconsider
accompanying the troops
on the front line.
I have a feeling the situation will likely
call for a political decision to be made.
They'll need someone
who can do that instantly.
It's still too dangerous.
Policymakers don't have
to lead the charge.
Didn't you want to be PM in ten years?
But we have to ensure
Japan's still around in ten years.
That's more important
than being its leader.
We've got young talent.
They're in various sectors.
public and private.
And with you here. finding the next leader
won't be a problem.
You've helped me stay the course.
Thank you.
That's absurd.
You should be thanking Akasaka.
I'll leave the rest to you.
Yeah.
Save me Party Secretary.
When carrying out
this Yashiori Operation...
...there's a very real possibility that
you will risk acute radiation exposure!
Those who are here.
aren't guaranteed to leave here alive!
Yet we must see this to the end!
We are here to show the whole world
this country's greatest strength!
The SDF now has the opportunity
to be the last line of the defense
against this great threat!
The world's relying on you...
and so is the future of Japan!
Do your best!
Right! Roll out!
Yes. sir!
Northwest wind. two meters.
The creature's plume
is heading toward Tokyo Bay.
Damage is estimated to be minimal.
All units. In position. Standing by.
Contact from U.S. military headquarters.
U.S. attack drone squadron airborne
in designated holding patterns.
No problems.
All systems are go.
Awaiting your orders. sir.
But we still haven't received word
from Tokyo of the evacuation.
We've got one shot.
We can't miss this opportunity.
Let's continue.
Tell the local governments to enforce
curfew order. Commander Tanba.
Roger that.
Alert each local government
in the Kanto region.
Have them issue a 50-hour indoor
confinement curfew for all citizens.
Everyone is to refrain from going out.
Roger that!
Contact from Shimbashi.
All unmanned vehicles have been detached.
Passing zero point.
Now. commence Operation Yashiori.
Phase One. Diversion. begin!
Diversion success! Train blasts effective!
Operation. Phase Two.
Commence air force attack.
Roger that. Contact U.S. forces.
The target is discharging photons
from its dorsal fins!
It's taking down the drones.
Everything's going according to plan.
First drone sortie destroyed.
No matter. We'll wear it down.
We have to keep Gojira emitting radiation
until it's spent.
Second drone sortie. all destroyed.
Third drone sortie. commencing attack!
Target. moving to kill point one.
Third sortie. destroyed!
The contamination zone is growing.
Deputy Chief. the radiation dose
will exceed the planned area.
If we stop now.
all of this will have been for nothing.
Please continue the attack.
Fourth sortie. destroyed!
We can't let up. Launch the fifth sortie.
Target has stopped discharging its beam
from its dorsal fins.
Fifth sortie. still engaging the target.
How can it do that?
Fifth sortie. destroyed.
Gojira's plume.
it exceeds twice the expected size.
Stay strong. We have to endure.
Sixth sortie. commence attack!
The volume of radiation is decreasing.
Confirming that the target's flame
has ceased.
Target luring to kill point one complete.
Okay. onto Phase Three.
Commence stationary blasting.
Ignite!
Volume of radiation has fallen
to expected value.
Fixing target at kill point one.
Roger that. Phase Four.
Guided blast. commence!
The target has fallen!
Kill point one. fixing complete.
Operation in the final phase.
Special crane platoon. Commence!
Roger that! 1st platoon. forward!
Crane Platoon 01.
Hydra-slayer 01. move out!
Cranes 12 to 14.
move to combat formation behind BP2.
Hydra-slayer 01. Crane 11.
and BP1 in the deployment zone.
Crane 11. Hydra-slayer 01. Roger that!
Standby in defensive circle
with engines ready.
All special vehicles.
deploy outriggers and approach BP1.
After that. commence injection.
Crane 12 and BP2. deployment complete.
Hydra-slayer 01. Crane 15.
All 15 vehicles. deployed.
Starting connection. Over.
Crane 15. Hydra-slayer 01. Roger that.
Stay at outer operation range.
All units. commence injection!
Inject the coagulant!
All vehicles. initiate pumps!
RC operational!
Okay! Raise output pressure
to the maximum output!
Target the mouth as much as possible!
Dosage. 20% has been administered.
Dosage. 30% has been administered.
Crane Platoon 1. Destroyed.
The dosage is working!
The target's movements are slowing down!
Now or never. We can't let it slip away.
All train bombs. now!
Gojira. It's fallen again!
Commander Tanba.
please send out the second platoon!
2nd and 3rd platoons. advance!
Freeze it once and for all!
All vehicles. administer all at once!
50% of the dosage has been administered!
The tanks up to number 20 are empty.
Roger.
Switch tanks to number 21 and above!
Dosage. 60% has been administered!
75% has been administered.
We've exceeded the projected
minimum dosage of blood coagulant.
90% has been administered!
100% has been administered.
We've reached the critical point!
The target's skin is stiffening!
Please follow the calculation.
Did it work?
The target has resumed activity!
Everyone evacuate! Everyone evacuate!
All vehicles change positions! Hurry!
Special Construction 03.
all vehicles. maximum losses!
Abandon equipment
and evacuate to holding area!
Chest temperature has dropped
to -196 degrees.
Gojira has been completely silenced.
Operation Yashiori has been completed.
Thank you.
You were remarkable.
That was too close.
Less than an hour left until launch.
That was too close for comfort.
It's all thanks
to the acting prime minister
for succeeding in convincing the French.
Everyone.
Take a look at this survey data.
Ah.
Gojira's new isotope
has a half-life of 20 days.
It'll reduce to less than half in a month.
Almost gone in two or three years.
Yes. With this there's hope
for a decontamination.
Hmm.
Thank goodness.
Good work.
Very soon. the Satomi Cabinet
will take full responsibility and resign.
And I suppose that falls nicely in line
with what you had planned.
It wasn't my idea.
It was Prime Minister Satomi's decision.
The capital and government
are now in ruins.
We'll rebuild them into
a functioning structure.
If the next provisional government passes
the bill on Giant Unidentified Life-Forms.
that'll be the time to dissolve the Diet.
and hold a general election.
A new cabinet to face 3.6 million refugees
and a dying country.
That's what we're gonna need
for the sake of our future.
Scrapping and building has always led
to our country's growth.
So we'll build back again.
The countdown was merely suspended.
but the moment Godzilla resumes activity.
it'll restart.
3.526 seconds to launch.
That was awfully lenient of you.
Something had to be done
to reassure the world.
Now Japan... no...
all of mankind must coexist with Gojira.
You leaked the data to France. didn't you?
France deserved to know
but also the rest of the world.
I broke a promise. but regret nothing.
I respect how you do whatever's necessary.
Don't quit.
You better not quit.
I have a clear vision for the future
where I'm the U.S. President
and you're the Prime Minister.
So I'd be your Japanese puppet.
The fact remains.
the casualties were high.
Accountability always comes with the job.
However a politician must decide
whether to own it or not.
I myself choose to own it.
Well. as Maki said...
do whatever you want.
But now's not the time to quit.
Especially since this crisis
is far from over.